Front-end developer - React

Colima, Mexico vsjoseluisvs@gmail.com Tel: +52 314 1481697

Career Summary

I have been working for 3 year and a half as a Software Engineer. I love programming, I enjoy learning and sharing my knowledge. I have experience with JavaScript, TypeScript, React, NodeJS, AWS. In my last project I worked as a Front-end developer in the development of a web application with React. The project was carried out using the Kanban methodology.

Certifications

AWS Certified Solutions Architect – Associate (https://www.credly.com/badges/ab6dc01f-aa86-4faa-a934-c4fe83e9c955?source=linked_in_profile)

Contest

- Hack Colima 2018:Seguridad + Paz

Education

University of Colima, Colima, Mexico BS, Software engineering. Degree pending

Jun. 2015 - Jun. 2019

Firebase

Python

Summary of Qualifications

- JavaScript
 TypeScript
 React
 NodeJS
 Electron
 Jest
 GraphQL
- React
 Redux
 GraphQL
 AWS
 MySQL
 React Native

Languages

Spanish (native speaker)English

Career History

EPAM Anywhere, Guadalajara, Mexico

Frontend developer

- Worked on UI implementation with React and TypeScript
- Use version control tool Git
- Performing bug fixings
- API integrations with the front-end

GLOBANT, Guadalajara, Mexico

Web UI Developer, Jr Adv

Worked with Ruby on Rails with React, where I learned how to integrate the backend with the frontend

- Complete database migrations with Ruby on Rails and ActiveRecord
- Use version control tool Git
- Use of Devise for user authentication
- Write tests with Rspec
- Create background job with sidekiq

Jan. 2022 – Present

Aug. 2021 – Jan. 2022

DENSITY LABS, Guadalajara, Mexico

Full Stack

- Worked with electron, NodeJS, React to create a bot that runs on a desktop application
- Experience with puppeteer to create a bot to automate tasks
- Worked with React and Bootstrap, to develop the view of the desktop app
- Worked with Node.js in the backend, to create the interaction with the API's

IO CONNECT SERVICES, Guadalajara, Mexico

Nov. 2019 - Nov. 2020

Dec. 2020 - Jul. 2021

Jr. Software Engineer

- Involved in the development of scripts using Python 3 and Apache beam
- Wrote Python scripts to transform CSV files to a JSON model and upload to Google Cloud
- Involved in the creation of ETL in AWS
- Create triggers in MvSOL
- Worked in the creation a Docker container, with a Mule application in it

TATA CONSULTANCY SERVICES, Guadalajara, Mexico

Jan. 2019 - Oct. 2019

Jr. Software Engineer

- Worked with Java EE 8
- Experience in writing PowerShell scripts

MOBILE APP TO SAVE ANIMALS

Sep. 2018

I participated in "Hack Colima 2018: Seguridad + Paz", where we created a mobile app in Android Studio with Java and Firebase, to rescue animals from the street.

Tech Experience: Java, Android Studio, Firebase

SALES SYSTEM FOR AUTOMOBILE

Aug. 2017 - Dec 2017

Designed and developed custom Java web application to sell automobiles. Used HTML, CSS, Node JS and JavaScript

Tech Experience: Java, HTML, CSS, Node JS and JavaScript